Granville Hicks Papers
Granville Hicks Papers
- Writings
  - Lectures
    - Untitled, alphabetical by subject
      - Decline of English novel, debate with Stanley Hyman (Box 94)
      - Fascism (Box 94)
      - Grafton (Box 94)
      - Literary criticism (Box 94)
      - Marxism course (Box 94)
      - Small towns (Box 94)
  - "Literary Horizons" columns, published in Saturday Review
    Articles are in alphabetical order by title, followed by a small number of dated but untitled items. At the end is a set of file cards with an alphabetical list of articles; this index was not donated as part of the collection, but was compiled by staff.
    - By title, A - D (Box 134)
    - By title, Ea - I (Box 135)
    - By title, J - O (Box 136)
    - By title, P - Sou (Box 137)
    - By title, Sp - Y (Box 138)
    - By date, 1958-1969 (Box 138)
    - File cards, alphabetical listing of articles (Box 139)
  - Macmillan Company reader's reports
    - A - Ar, 2 folders (Box 94)
    - As - Cary, 15 folders (Box 95)
    - Cass - Dug, 14 folders (Box 96)
    - Duh - Gw, 14 folders (Box 97)
    - Ha - Ko, 15 folders (Box 98)
    - Kr - Mor, 14 folders (Box 99)
    - Morg - Ri, 15 folders (Box 100)
    - Ro - Sty, 13 folders (Box 101)
    - Ta - Z, 15 folders (Box 102)
  - Miscellany
    - Published
      - 4-H Clubs of Rensselaer County: The First Twenty-five Years 1920-1945 (Box 103)
      - "Hicks Takes Anti-FDR Reviewer To Task", Feb. 4, 1952; Letter to the Editor The New Leader (Box 103)
      - The Inter-Racial Forum Opportunity, May 1923 (Box 103)
      - "Is Understanding With Russia Indispensable to World Peace?" Wake Up, America!, undated (Box 103)
      - Isabel Carleton Wilde Collection of Early American Sculpture exhibit catalog Foreword, 1933 (Box 103)
      - "A Letter to Robert Hillyer" The New Republic, Oct. 20, 1937 (Box 103)
      - "The New Light: an Easter Cantata", text by G. Hicks (Box 103)
      - "On Leaving the Communist Party", drafts (Box 103)
      - "On Leaving the Communist Party", Oct. 4, 1939; Letter to the Editor The New Republic (Box 103)
      - Plekhanov, George vol. Art and Society: a Marxist Analysis, 1936; Introduction by G. Hicks (Box 103)
      - Proletarian Literature in the United States, Preface to section on literary criticism (Box 103)
      - Reed, John. Ten Days That Shook the World, 1935; Introduction by G. Hicks to first Modern Library edition (Box 103)
      - Reed, John. Ten Days That Shook the World, 1967; Introduction by G. Hicks to New American Library edition (Box 103)
      - The Student Liberal (Box 103)
      - Wells, H.G. Marxism vs. Liberalism: an interview (with Joseph Stalin), 1935; Introduction by G. Hicks (Box 103)
      - Wilder, Thornton. The Bridge of San Luis Rey, 1962; Introduction by G. Hicks (Box 103)
      - Wright Morris: a Reader, Introduction by G. Hicks (draft) (Box 103)
      - Wright Morris: a Reader, Introduction by G. Hicks (draft) with annotations by Wright Morris (Box 103)
    - Unpublished non-fiction
      - "Abishag" (Box 103)
      - "The American Magazine Since 1900" (Box 103)
      - "The American Story" (Box 103)
      - "Annals of Crime: the Friends of Beany" (Box 103)
      - [Autobiographical fragments] (Box 103)
      - "The British Novel Since 1930" (Box 103)
      - Brown, Lloyd L. Iron City, 1951; review (Box 103)
      - "The Camp Log", June 28 - Sept. 7, 1925; autobiographical (Box 103)
      - "A Country Worth Seeing: Confessions of an Ex-Stay-at-Home" (Box 103)
      - Dorothy and Granville Hicks' courtship chronology, incomplete; authorship ambiguous (Box 103)
      - [Dreams], April 1968 - July 1969 (Box 103)
      - "The Evangelical Mind" (Box 103)
      - "Farewell to Academe" (Box 103)
      - "For Dorothy" (Box 103)
      - [Granville Hicks' 50th anniversary report of his graduation from Harvard], autobiographical (Box 103)
      - "History is Made", drafts I - III (Box 89)
      - "History is Made", clippings (Box 89)
      - "History is Made", Hicks' defense (Box 89)
      - "Is the Small Town Doomed?", Woman's Home Companion (Box 103)
      - [Journal], June 19 - Aug. 26, 1922; Dennison Manufacturing Co. summer job (autobiographical) (Box 103)
      - "Max Lerner and the New Liberalism" (Box 103)
      - "Max Lerner's Kind of Liberalism" (Box 103)
      - "Miss Godson, Jim Moriarty, and My Bloody Nose", autobiographical (Box 103)
      - [Narrative poetry project] (Box 103)
      - "New Masses" (Box 104)
      - "Nothing But the Truth", autobiographical (Box 104)
      - "On a Steam Shovel Seen at Night" (Box 104)
      - "A Place in the Country", autobiographical (Box 104)
      - [Proletarian literature pamphlet], 1933-34; notes, outline (Box 104)
      - [Proletarian literature pamphlet], drafts 1 - 5; 5 folders (Box 104)
      - [Proletarian literature pamphlet], fragment by Robert Gorham Davis (Box 104)
      - [Proletarian literature pamphlet], fragment; 3 folders (Box 104)
      - "The Rococo Romanticists" (Box 104)
      - "The Side Show" (Box 104)
      - "Some of My Best Friends" (Box 104)
      - "Sonnet for a Mood" (Box 104)
      - "Sonnet in a Library" (Box 104)
      - [Soviet-German Pact fortnight], autobiographical (Box 104)
      - "Varieties of Fellow-Traveling" (Box 104)
      - "Wedding Belles" (American Cancer Society fund-raiser), 1955; script (Box 104)
      - "When the Mountain Fell" (Box 104)
    - Unpublished fiction
      - "Chuck" (Box 104)
      - "Dog and Cat" (Box 104)
      - "Green Leaves on the Apple Trees" (Box 104)
      - "Old Man French" (Box 104)
      - "Solid as Gilbraltar" (Box 104)
      - "Take Care of Yourself" (Box 104)
      - Short story [untitled], 2 foldes (Box 104)
      - Short story fragments [untitled (Box 104)
      - Untitled, may be autobiographical (Box 104)
      - Untitled fragment (Box 104)
- Memorabilia
  - Address list (Box 105)
  - Awkward usage examples (Box 105)
  - Book lists (Box 105)
  - Caricatures - artist unknown (Box 105)
  - Chronology, May - Dec. 1957 (Box 105)
  - College course notes
    - Astronomy, 1921-1922 (Box 105)
    - English, 1921-1922; 2 folders (Box 105)
    - English, 1928-1929; 2 folders (Box 105)
    - English, undated; 4 folders (Box 105)
    - History, 1922 (Box 105)
    - New Testament, 1923-1924 (Box 105)
    - Old Testament, 1924-1925 (Box 105)
    - Principles of Economics, 1923 (Box 105)
    - Religion, undated; 9 folders (Box 105/106)
    - Social ethics, 1922-1925; 6 folders (Box 106)
  - College course writings
    - "A Brief Criticism of the Plays of Christopher Marlowe" (Box 107)
    - "The Influence of the Bible on the Miracle Plays" (Box 107)
    - "John Webster, Poet and Dramatist" (Box 107)
    - "Michael Servetus" (Box 107)
    - "A Monologue with Interruptions" (Box 107)
    - "The Root and Cure of Sin" (Orphism and Plato) (Box 107)
  - Cross-country trip, Dorothy Hicks' journals, 1948 (Box 107)
  - Cross-country trip, G. Hicks' expense notations, 1948 (Box 107)
  - Cross-country trip, maps, 1948 (Box 107)
  - Cross-country trip, pamphlets, 1948 (Box 107)
  - Cross-country trip, miscellany, 1948 (Box 107)
  - Financial miscellany (Box 107)
  - Grade school report cards (Box 107)
  - Handwritten notes, miscellaneous (Box 107)
  - Joint Legislative Fact-Finding Committee on Un-American Activities in the State of Washington - Subpoena, July 13, 1948 (Box 107)
  - Kiwanis Club of Wynantskill, New York. Certificate of Appreciation (Box 107)
  - National War Fund Campaign Citation, 1943 (Box 107)
  - Obituary, New York Times, 1982 (Box 107)
  - Pacific Northwest Writers' Conference, 1948; agenda and name tag (Box 107)
  - Photographs (Box 107)
  - Poetry, authors unknown (Box 107)
  - Prophecy of Lincoln School Class of 1915 (Box 107)
  - RPI grade books, 3 folders (Box 107)
  - "Serendipity on Flight 576" for Granville Hicks by George Riddle (Box 107)
  - Syracuse University Library Associates membership cards (Box 107)
  - Miscellany (Box 107)
- Printed material
  - Book reviews, books by Hicks
    - Behold Trouble (Box 110)
    - Figures of Transition (Box 110)
    - The First to Awaken (Box 110)
    - Granville Hicks in the New Masses (Box 110)
    - The Great Tradition (Box 110)
    - I Like America (Box 110)
    - John Reed: the Making of a Revolutionary (Box 110)
    - The Letters of Lincoln Steffens (Box 110)
    - Literary Horizons (Box 110)
    - The Living Novel (Box 110)
    - Only One Storm (A - N) (Box 110)
    - Only One Storm (O - Z and unidentified) (Box 110)
    - Part of the Truth (A - M) (Box 110)
    - Part of the Truth (N - Z and unidentified) (Box 110)
    - Small Town (A - M) (Box 110)
    - Small Town (N - Z and unidentified) (Box 110)
    - There Was a Man In Our Town (Box 110)
    - Where We Came Out (Box 110)
  - Clippings
    - Articles about
      - [General], to 1937 (Box 111)
      - City vs. Country Life March 17, 1972 (Oversize 1)
      - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute dismissal, See Correspondence - Subject files: RPI dismissal.
      - Miscellany, 1938 (Box 111)
      - Hicks' Harvard appointment, 1938 (Box 111)
      - Miscellany, 1939 (Box 111)
      - Resignation from Communist Party, 1939 (Box 111)
      - [General], 1940-1952 (Box 111)
      - House Committee on Un-American activities, 1953 (Box 111)
      - Miscellany, 1954-1982 (Box 111)
    - Miscellaneous clippings
      - Dorothy Yankouski trial (Box 111)
      - Environment and technology (Box 111)
      - Literature (Box 111)
      - Mass culture and society, 1960s-1970s (Box 111)
      - [Miscellaneous], to 1950 (Box 111)
    - Troy Record clippings (Box 111)
  - Corning Glass Center tour guidebook (Box 108)
  - Drew University Newark Conference Annual Convocation program, 1947 (Box 108)
  - Fine art prints, British, French, Spanish (Box 108)
  - Fine arts prints, Dutch, Flemish, American; miscellaneous (Box 108)
  - Fine arts prints, Italian (Box 108)
  - "The First Forty Years of the Book-of-the-Month Club" (Box 108)
  - Framingham High School Graduation program, 1919 (Box 110)
  - French's Budget Plays, Ten Dollar Royalty Plays and Entertainment (Box 108)
  - Garson, Barbara. Macbird, 1966 (Box 108)
  - Hampshire County Progressive Club Forum programs (Box 108)
  - Harvard Club of Boston. Bulletin, Jan. 1939 (Box 108)
  - Harvard Commencement, 1923 (Box 108)
  - "In Memorium Late Spanish 'Reds'" (Box 108)
  - John Burroughs in Roxbury (Box 108)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Foundation, 1939-1940; Reports of the Secretary and the Treasurer (Box 108)
  - The Little Magazines - catalog of Kraus Reprint titles (Box 108)
  - Modern Authors Henry W. Wenning. Modern Rare Books catalog no. 9 (Box 108)
  - The Modern Library and Vintage Books: a Complete Catalogue and Subject Guide (Box 108)
  - New Masses editorial announcement, flyer (Box 108)
  - New York State topographical maps, 2 folders (Box 108)
  - Ohio University, Athens. Faculty-Staff Directory, 1967-1968 (Box 109)
  - Pamphlets
    - Air power. Washington, D.C., Aeronautical Chamber of Commerce of America, Inc., 1944?; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Alberti, Rafael. A Spectre is haunting Europe: poems of revolutionary Spain. New York, Critics Group, 1936; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - America speaks for Earl Browder. New York, Citizens' Committee to Free Earl Browder, 1941 (Box 112)
    - Arsenal of facts, prepared by Labor Research Association. New York, International Publishers, 1938; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Ault, Leslie. Challenge to fear. Woodstock, New York, Branch Publishers, 1937; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Barnes, Harry Elmer. The Chickens of the interventionist liberals have come home to roost. Chicago, American Renaissance Book Club, undated; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Barton, Ann.Mother Bloor, Feb 1935 (Box 112)
    - Bittelman, Alex.The Communist Party in Action. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Sep 1932 (Box 112)
    - Bittelman, Alex.From Left-Socialism to Communism. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Sep 1933 (Box 112)
    - Bittelman, Alex.Milestones in the History of the Communist Party. International Labor Defense, Aug 1937 (Box 112)
    - Blache, Robert.Spain's October. International Labor Defense, 1935 (Box 112)
    - Boorstin, Daniel [et al.] Anti-Semitism: a threat to democracy, no imprint (Box 112)
    - Browder, Earl. Civil War in Nationalist China. Chicago, Labor Unity Publishing Association, 1927 (Box 112)
    - Browder, Earl. The Democratic front for jobs, security, democracy and peace. New York, Workers Library Publishers, 1938 (Box 112)
    - Browder, Earl. The 1940 elections: how the people can win. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Inc., 1939 (Box 112)
    - Browder, Earl. The Road ahead to victory and lasting peace. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Inc., 1944 (Box 112)
    - Browder, Earl. Social and national security. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Inc., 1938 (Box 112)
    - Browder, Earl. Unity for peace and democracy. New York, Workers Library Publishers, 1939 (Box 112)
    - Buckharin, N.. Culture in Two Worlds. New York, Union Labor, 1934 (Box 112)
    - The Case of the 16 Poles. New York, National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Inc., undated; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Citizen in name only. Richmond, Virginia, Southern Electoral Reform League, undated (Box 112)
    - Coleman, Jerry. A Square Deal for the Farmer. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Oct 1938 (Box 112)
    - Communist International. 7th Congress, Moscow, 1935. Resolutions, including also the closing speech of Georgi Dimitroff. New York, Workers Library Publishers. (Box 112)
    - Communist political education. London, Communist Party of Great Britain, 1933 (Box 112)
    - Confession of Faith. Communist Party of Massachusetts, undated (Box 112)
    - The Constitution of the United States with the Amendments also the Declaration of Independence. Introduction by Earl Browder. New York, International Publishers, 1938; c1937 (Box 112)
    - Contempt of Congress: the trial of Earl Browder. Yonkers, Earl Browder, 1951? (Box 112)
    - Culture and the Crisis. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Oct 1932 (Box 112)
    - Declaration of Principles and Constitution of the Communist Party of Massachusetts. Boston, The Communist Party of Massachusetts, Sep 1937 (Box 112)
    - Dennis, Eugene. America at the crossroads: postwar problems and Communist policy. New York, New Century Publishers, 1945 (Box 112)
    - Dimitroff, Georgi. Working class unity: bulwark against fascism. New York, Workers Library Publishers, 1935; 2 copies (Box 112)
    - Duclos, Jacques. Communism, science and culture. New York, International Publishers, 1939 (Box 112)
    - Engels, Frederick. Socialism - utopian and scientific. Chicago, Charles H. Kerr and Company, 1908? (Box 112)
    - Engels, Frederick. Socialism - utopian and scientific. New York, International Publishers, 1935 (Box 112)
    - Fairness of the air: a case history from the operations of the Columbia Broadcasting System. [N.Y.] Columbia Broadcasting System, 1944 (Box 112)
    - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley. Earl Browder: the man from Kansas. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Inc., 1941 (Box 112)
    - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley. Questions and answers on the Browder case. New York, Citizens' Committee to Free Earl Browder, 1942? (Box 112)
    - Forsythe, Robert. The World Gone Mad. New York, New Masses, 1935 and 1936 (Box 112)
    - Foster, William Z. The Menace of American imperialism/ Dennis, Eugene. America needs the Communist Party. New York, New Century Publishers, 1945 (Box 112)
    - Foster, William Z. [et al.] Marxism-Leninism vs. revisionism. New York, New Century Publishers, 1946 (Box 112)
    - Foster, William Z. Soviet democracy and the war. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Inc., 1943 (Box 112)
    - Frankfield, Phil. The Intelligent Voter's Guide in Massachusetts.Boston, The Communist Party of Massachusetts, 1943 (Box 112)
    - Gaer, Joseph and Lamb, Robert K. The Answer is full employment. New York, CIO Political Action Committee, undated; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Garlin, Sender. Enemies of the peace: profile of the 'Hate-Russia' gang. New York, New Century Publishers, 1945; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Garlin, Sender. The Real Huey P. Long. New York, Workers Library Publishers, 1945; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Geddes, Virgil. The Melodramadness of Eugene O'Neill. Brookfield, Conn., Brookfield Players, Inc., 1934; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Geddes, Virgil. The Theatre of dreadful nights. Brookfield, Conn., Brookfield Players, Inc., 1934; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Geddes, Virgil. Towards revolution in the theatre. Brookfield, Conn., Brookfield Mayers, Inc., 1933; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Gitlow, Benjamin. Some Plain Words on Communist Unity. New York, Workers Age Publishing., undated (Box 112)
    - Gorky, Maxim. Days with Lenin. New York, International Publishers, 1932. (Box 112)
    - Half a million forgotten people: the story of the cotton textile workers. New York Textile Workers Union of America, CIO., 1944; 2 copies; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Hamilton, Franklin W. Thoreau on the art of writing. Flint, Michigan, Walden Press, 1967 (Box 113)
    - Jobs, Security, Democracy and Peace. Communist Party of Massachusetts, undated (Box 113)
    - Hauser, Jacob. Dark metropolis. Holt, Minn., Hagglund, 1932; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Ibsen. New York, Critics Group, 1937 (Box 113)
    - Jarrboe, George. The Unknown soldier speaks. Holt, Minn., Hagglund, 1932; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Klingender, F.J. Marxism and modern art. New York, International Publishers, 1945 (Box 113)
    - Krupskaya, N. How Lenin studied Marx. London, Labour Monthly, undated (Box 113)
    - Herberg, Will. The Heritage of the Civil War. New York, Workers Age Publishing, undated (Box 113)
    - Holcombe, Arthur N. et alii. Official Report of the Committee on the Investigation of Police Tactics in Charlestown on May 17, 1934., undated (Box 113)
    - Lawson, John Howard. A Southern Welcome. New York, The National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners, Nov 1934 (Box 113)
    - Lenin, vol. I. A Letter to American workers. New York, International Publishers, 1934 (Box 113)
    - Lenin on the Jewish question. New York, International Publishers, 1934; reprinted 1936; 2 copies (Box 113)
    - Let's make it "Guild First". Committee for Guild Democracy., undated (Box 113)
    - Letter of an Old Bolshevik. New York, Rand School Press., 1937 (Box 113)
    - Lewis, H.H. Red renaissance: a group of poems. Holt, Minn., Hagglund, 1930; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Lewis, H.H. Salvation. Holt, Minn., Hagglund, 1934; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Lewis, H.H. Thinking of Russia. Holt, Minn., Hagglund, 1932; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Lifshitz, Mikhail. The Philosophy of art of Karl Marx. New York, Critics Group, 1938; 2 copies (Box 113)
    - Magil, A. B.. The Real Father Coughlin. New York, Workers Library Publishers, May 1939 (Box 113)
    - Mao Tse-tung. China's new democracy. New York, New Century Publishers, 1945 (Box 113)
    - Mao Tse-Tung. The Fight for a new China. New York, New Century Publishers, 1945 (Box 113)
    - Marti, Jose. Poemes choisis. Paris, Emile-Paul Freres, 1929 (Box 113)
    - Marx, Karl and Engels, Frederick. Manifesto of the Communist Party. Chicago, Charles H. Kerr and Co., (inscribed D.D.H. [Dorothy Hicks] from N.A. [Newton Arvin] with affectionate regard. 23 July 1931), undated (Box 113)
    - Marx, Karl and Engels, Friedrich. Manifesto of the Communist Party. New York, International Publishers, 1932; reprinted 1935; 2 copies (Box 113)
    - Marxist study courses: History of the working class. Lesson I: the Great French Revolution. New York, International Publishers, 1931; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Marxist study courses: History of the working class. Lesson II: the English Industrial Revolution and Chartism. New York, International Publishers, 1932; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Marxist study courses: History of the working class. Lesson III: the Revolution of 1848 in France and Germany. New York, International Publishers, undated; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Marxist study courses: History of the working class. Lesson IV: the First International and the Paris Commune. New York, International Publishers, undated; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Marxist study courses: Political economy. Lesson I: Marxist theory of value. New York, International Publishers, undated; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Miff, P.. Heroic China New York, Workers Library Publishers, Jan 1937; Apr 1937 (Box 113)
    - Ming, Wang. The Revolutionary Movement in the Colonial Counties New York, Workers Library Publishers, Dec 1935 (Box 113)
    - Minor, Robert. Free Earl Browder! New York, Workers Library Publishers, Inc., 1941 (Box 113)
    - Mr. President: free Earl Browder! New York, Citizens Committee to Free Earl Browder, 1942 (Box 113)
    - Naft, Stephen. 100 Questions to the Communists. New York, Rand School Press, 1939 (Box 113)
    - Nearing, Scott. Europe-West and East. New York, Vanguard Press, undated (Box 113)
    - Nearing, Scott. The Rise and Decline of Christian Civilization., undated; including a flyer announcing the informal lecture of Harry Elmer Barnes on "Let's Keep out of the European Mess this TIme!" (Box 113)
    - North, Joseph. The Case of Earl Browder: Why he should be freed. New York, Citizens' Committee to Free Earl Browder, 1942 (Box 113)
    - Novitsky, Pavel I. Cervantes and Don Quixote: a Socio-historical interpretation. New York, Critics' Group, 1936; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - O'Connor, Harvey. How Mellon got rich. New York, International Pamphlets, 1933; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
    - Olgin, M.J. That man Browder. New York, Workers Library Publishers, Inc., 1936 (Box 113)
    - Olgin, M.J. Why Communism? New York, Workers Library Publishers, 1935 (Box 113)
    - Oneal, James. Some Pages of Party History. New York, Workers Library Publishers, 1935 (Box 113)
    - Parker, Quentin. We are weaving! Philadelphia, 1934; inscribed by author (Box 113)
    - Petersen, Arnold. Karl Marx and Marxism. New York, New York Labor News Company, 1933 (Box 113)
    - Petersen, Arnold. Proletarian Democracy vs. Dictatorship and Despotism. New York, New York Labor News Company, 1932 (Box 113)
    - Petersen, Arnold. W.Z. Foster - Renegade or Spy?. New York, New York Labor News Company, 1932 (Box 113)
    - Plan E., undated (Box 113A)
    - Plekhanov, George vol. Art and society: a Marxist analysis. Introduction by Granville Hicks. New York, Critics Group, 1936; (with annotations by Hicks) (Box 113)
    - Plekhanov, George vol. Henrik Ibsen. Stuttgart, P. Singer, 1908 (Box 113)